
                                <day-2019-01>
                                    <Day><DayId>recYxR1fF3a2DghD4</DayId><createdTime>2022-01-08T23:07:26Z</createdTime><Assignment>--- Day 1: The Tyranny of the Rocket Equation ---
Santa has become stranded at the edge of the Solar System while delivering presents to other planets! To accurately calculate his position in space, safely align his warp drive, and return to Earth in time to save Christmas, he needs you to bring him measurements from fifty stars.

Collect stars by solving puzzles. Two puzzles will be made available on each day in the Advent calendar; the second puzzle is unlocked when you complete the first. Each puzzle grants one star. Good luck!

The Elves quickly load you into a spacecraft and prepare to launch.

At the first Go / No Go poll, every Elf is Go until the Fuel Counter-Upper. They haven't determined the amount of fuel required yet.

Fuel required to launch a given module is based on its mass. Specifically, to find the fuel required for a module, take its mass, divide by three, round down, and subtract 2.

For example:

For a mass of 12, divide by 3 and round down to get 4, then subtract 2 to get 2.
For a mass of 14, dividing by 3 and rounding down still yields 4, so the fuel required is also 2.
For a mass of 1969, the fuel required is 654.
For a mass of 100756, the fuel required is 33583.
The Fuel Counter-Upper needs to know the total fuel requirement. To find it, individually calculate the fuel needed for the mass of each module (your puzzle input), then add together all the fuel values.

What is the sum of the fuel requirements for all of the modules on your spacecraft?

To play, please identify yourself via one of these services:</Assignment><Year><Days></Days></Year><OnlineGames>recudDCFSz4R7ujD2</OnlineGames><Answer>3256794</Answer><SampleInputValues>101005
139223
112833
70247
131775
106730
118388
138683
80439
71060
120862
67201
70617
79783
114813
77907
78814
107515
113507
81865
88130
75120
66588
56023
98080
128472
96031
118960
54069
112000
62979
105518
73342
52270
128841
68267
70789
94792
100738
102331
83082
77124
97360
86165
66120
139042
50390
105308
94607
58225
77894
118906
127277
101446
58897
93876
53312
117154
77448
62041
99069
87375
134854
108561
126406
53809
90760
121650
79573
134734
148021
84263
54390
132706
148794
67302
146885
76108
76270
54548
146920
145282
129509
144139
141713
62547
149898
96746
83583
107758
63912
142036
112281
91775
75809
82250
144667
140140
98276
103479</SampleInputValues><Day></Day><Status>Done</Status><Subject>The Tyranny of the Rocket Equation</Subject><Part2>--- Part Two ---
During the second Go / No Go poll, the Elf in charge of the Rocket Equation Double-Checker stops the launch sequence. Apparently, you forgot to include additional fuel for the fuel you just added.

Fuel itself requires fuel just like a module - take its mass, divide by three, round down, and subtract 2. However, that fuel also requires fuel, and that fuel requires fuel, and so on. Any mass that would require negative fuel should instead be treated as if it requires zero fuel; the remaining mass, if any, is instead handled by wishing really hard, which has no mass and is outside the scope of this calculation.

So, for each module mass, calculate its fuel and add it to the total. Then, treat the fuel amount you just calculated as the input mass and repeat the process, continuing until a fuel requirement is zero or negative. For example:

A module of mass 14 requires 2 fuel. This fuel requires no further fuel (2 divided by 3 and rounded down is 0, which would call for a negative fuel), so the total fuel required is still just 2.
At first, a module of mass 1969 requires 654 fuel. Then, this fuel requires 216 more fuel (654 / 3 - 2). 216 then requires 70 more fuel, which requires 21 fuel, which requires 5 fuel, which requires no further fuel. So, the total fuel required for a module of mass 1969 is 654 + 216 + 70 + 21 + 5 = 966.
The fuel required by a module of mass 100756 and its fuel is: 33583 + 11192 + 3728 + 1240 + 411 + 135 + 43 + 12 + 2 = 50346.
What is the sum of the fuel requirements for all of the modules on your spacecraft when also taking into account the mass of the added fuel? (Calculate the fuel requirements for each module separately, then add them all up at the end.)</Part2><Name>day-2019-01</Name><LinkToAssignment>https://adventofcode.com/2019/day/01</LinkToAssignment><YearNumber>2019</YearNumber><Part2Answer>4882337</Part2Answer></Day>
                                </day-2019-01>                                
                            